Guide to the Whitney M. Young Jr. Memorial Foundation Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII: Subject Files
  - Ralph Bunche Commemorative Stamp (Box 57)
  - The Colonial Williamsburg Foundation (Box 57)
  - Columbia University Lectures, etc. (Box 57)
  - Congressional Black Caucus Dinner (Box 57)
  - Dickerson, Dennis Newspaper Article Centre Daily Times, 1/25/87 (Box 57)
  - Ideal Improvement Association (Box 57)
  - University of Illinois (Box 57)
  - Radcliffe College Interview Transcripts (Box 58)
  - Dorothy Height, Ann Tanneyhill and Frankie Adams Interview Transcripts (Box 58)
  - Radcliffe College, Schlesinger Library (oversized box) (Box 58)
  - General Daniel "Chappie" James Mem. Foundation. National Urban League (Box 59)
  - General Daniel "Chappie" James Memorial Foundation (Box 59)
  - Kentucky State University Report on Civil Rights (Box 59)
  - Kentucky State University Whitney Young College of Leadership Studies (Box 59)
  - The M.L. King Jr. Center for Social Change (Box 59)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson Library The LBJ Family, Austin, Texas (Box 59)
  - Links, Inc. (Box 59)
  - Memorial House (Box 59)
    [See Box 24]
  - N.A.A.C.P. (Box 59)
  - National Education Association (Box 59)
  - National Urban League, (5 folders ) (Box 59)
  - Printed material (photocopy) (Box 60)
  - Equal Opportunity Day Dinner, Nov. 18, 1971 (Box 60)
  - 1971 to 1976 (Box 60)
  - Search for new executive director of NUL, 1981 (Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous files regarding National Urban League (Box 62)
  - Negro Ensemble Company/Leontyne Price Benefit Concert
    - The Negro Ensemble Company, Inc. (Box 62)
    - Rosa L. Parks Cultural and Conference Center (Box 62)
    - Political Figures and Groups (Box 62)
    - Poston, Ted (Box 62)
    - Leontyne Price Benefit Concert (Box 62)
    - UNCF Benefit, 27 October 1987, (Stagebills) (Box 62)
    - Envelope containing, (photograph prints) (Box 62)
    - Box of various, (photographs and negatives) (Box 62)
    - Folder of concert programs and stationery from the benefit concert (Box 62)
    - H & G Financial Reports (Box 63)
    - Foundation Memos (Box 63)
    - Contribution Acknowledgements (Box 63)
    - Post Concert Party (Box 63)
    - H & G Letters of Agreements (Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous items (Box 63)
    - Envelope of stationery from the benefit concert (Box 63)
    - Concert Co-Chairs and Executive Committee (Box 63)
    - Press Lists (Box 63)
    - Cocktail Party (Box 63)
    - Checking account and Disbursements (Box 63)
    - Henry Ford (Box 63)
    - Minutes of Meetings and Budgets and Activity Reports (Box 63)
    - C. H. Seating and Related (Box 63)
    - Solicitation Lists and Letters (Box 63)
    - C.A.M. (Box 63)
    - L. Price (Box 63)
    - Leontyne Price Benefit Gift, (Photographs) (Box 63)
    - (Box 64)
    - Margaret Young re: benefit (Box 64)
    - Benefit Concert, 3/22/81 (Box 64)
  - Leontyne Price Benefit Concert
    - Benefit Concert Copies of Deposit Slips and Checks deposited by H & G, 1981 (Box 65)
    - H & G Financial Reports, 1981 (Box 65)
    - Benefit Concert Contributions, 1981 (Box 65)
    - Benefit Concert Contributions and Insufficient Fund (Box 65)
    - Benefit Concert Vouchers (Box 65)
    - Benefit Concert Invoices/Approved Vouchers/Copy of Payment Check, 1981 (Box 65)
  - Materials Race, Class and Poverty & Harold Sims
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence on Race, Class and Poverty (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous Materials on Race, Class and Poverty: bibliographies (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous Materials on Race, Class and Poverty (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous Materials on Race, Class and Poverty: Lecture Materials (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous Materials on Race, Class and Poverty: bibliographies (Box 66)
    - A. Phillip Randolph Dinner honoring Leontyne Price (Box 66)
    - Readers' Digest (Box 66)
    - Jackie Robinson Foundation (Box 66)
    - Harold Sims, (2 folders ) (Box 66)
  - Studio Museum in Harlem/Y.W.C.A.
    - The Studio Museum in Harlem (Box 67)
    - United Negro College Fund (Box 67)
    - Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania, (2 folders ) (Box 67)
    - Xavier University (Box 67)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence: Margaret B. Young, 3/16/[n.y.] (Box 67)
    - Miscellaneous CorrespondenceMargaret B. Young, Oct./Nov. 1981 (Box 67)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence: Margaret B. Young, 5/31/83 (Box 67)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence: Margaret B. Young, 9/11/84 (Box 67)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence: Margaret B. Young, 10/19/87 (Box 67)
    - Y.W.C.A. (Box 67)
  - Young, Whitney M. Jr.
    - Biographies (Box 68)
    - Biorelated data on WMY Jr. (Box 68)
    - Whitney M. Young Jr. Biography (Box 68)
    - Dennis Dickerson WMY Bio (Box 68)
    - Dennis Dickerson WMY Bio Ms., 1987 (Box 68)
    - Nancy Weiss WMY Biography (Box 68)
    - WMY Biographies (Box 68)
    - Correspondence related to inquiries for information on WMY Jr. (Box 68)
    - Proposed Biography Herb Shapiro (Box 68)
  - Young, Whitney M. Jr. Bust Files
    - Ed Wilson (Sculptor) 8391 Contracts/Agreements and Payments for sculpture project (Box 69)
    - Ed Wilson (Main Folder) Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1983-1991 (Box 69)
    - Placement of Bust, Memorial House, Simpsonville, Kentucky, 1988 (Box 69)
    - Columbia University Placement of WMY Bust, 1989 (Box 69)
  - Young, Whitney M. Bust Files
    - Whitney M. Young Magnet School Placement of WMY, Chicago, Illinois, 1991 (Box 70)
    - National Urban League Placement of WMY Bust, 1991 (Box 71)
    - Photographs of the bust (Box 71)
    - Ed Wilson (Box 71)
    - Young, Whitney M. Commemorative Stamp, 1981, (clippings) (Box 71)
    - Commemorative Stamp Miscellaneous Folder (Box 71)
    - Jackie Robinson Commemorative Stamp, 1982 (Box 71)
    - WMY Commemorative Stamp info (Box 71)
    - First Day of Issue folder, including brochure (Box 71)
    - Commemorative Stamp (Box 72)
    - WMY Commemorative Stamp NUL cachets (Box 72)
    - WMY Commemorative Stamp Art Craft Artmaster/Colorano "Silk" Cachets (Box 72)
    - Commemorative Stamp Negatives (Box 72)
    - Commemorative Stamp (Box 72)
  - Memorabilia
    - Documentaries and interviews (Box 73)
    - Plaques, magazine and newspaper clippings, photographs, artwork and brochures folders on posthumous honorary degrees, interviews and documentaries (Box 73)
    - Proposed memorials (Box 74)
    - Honorary Degrees, 1979; 19 April 1972 (Box 74)
    - Miscellaneous memorials (Box 74)
    - Memorial Concert (Box 74)
    - The McCreary Report (Box 74)
    - U.S. Senate, Hubert Humphrey (Box 74)
    - Albany, NY, (2 Folders ) (Box 74)
    - Atlanta University, (2 Folders ) (Box 74)
    - , Battle Creek, Michigan (Box 75)
    - Boston, Massachusetts (Box 75)
    - Bronx, New York (Box 75)
    - Chicago, Illinois, (4 folders ) (Box 75)
    - Cleveland, Ohio, (4 folders ) (Box 75)
    - Colorado Springs, Colorado (Box 75)
    - Columbus, Ohio, (2 folders ) (Box 75)
    - Dallas, Texas (Box 75)
    - Detroit, Michigan, (2 folders ) (Box 75)
    - Elizabeth, New Jersey (Box 75)
    - Fort Lauderdale, Florida (Box 75)
    - Fort Wayne, Indiana (Box 75)
    - Frankfort, Kentucky, (5 folders ) (Box 75)
    - Grand Rapids, Michigan (Box 75)
    - Inkster, Michigan (Box 75)
  - Young, Whitney M. Jr., Memorials
    - , Jersey City, NJ (Box 76)
    - Kalamazoo, MI (Box 76)
    - (Box 76)
    - Lagos, NIGERIA (Box 76)
    - Los Angeles, CA, (2 folders ) (Box 76)
    - Louisville, KY, (3 folders ) (Box 76)
    - Miami, FL (Box 76)
    - New Rochelle, NY, (2 folders ) (Box 76)
    - New York, NY, (7 folders ) (Box 76)
    - North Brunswick, NJ (Box 76)
    - Omaha, NE, (2 folders ) (Box 77)
    - Pittsburgh, PA (Box 77)
    - Plainfield, NJ (Box 77)
    - Portland, OR (Box 77)
    - St. Paul, MN, (2 folders ) (Box 77)
    - San Bernardino, CA (Box 77)
    - Shelbyville, KY (Box 77)
    - Stamford, CT, (2 folders ) (Box 77)
    - Staten Island, NY (Box 77)
    - Troy, NY (Box 77)
    - Valhalla, NY (Box 77)
    - Washington, DC, (5 folders ) (Box 77)
    - White Plains, NY, (2 folders ) (Box 77)
    - Yonkers, NY (Box 77)
  - Young, Whitney M. Jr., Papers and Collections
    - Atlanta University Request for the Whitney Young, Jr. Papers (Box 78)
    - Columbia University Whitney M. Young, Jr. Memorial Library of Social Work (Box 78)
    - Columbia University Tyrone Cannon (Box 78)
    - Columbia University Celestine Tutt. Personnel and Personal (Box 78)
    - Columbia University Library Proposal, Kenneth Lohf, 1991 (Box 78)
  - Young, Whitney M. Jr., Papers and CollectionsYoung, Whitney M. Sr.
    - Columbia University Clippings (Box 79)
    - Columbia University Miscellaneous Items, (2 folders ) (Box 79)
    - Kentucky State University Inquiry re: Whitney M. Young, Jr., 1976 (Box 79)
    - Library of Congress Re: Whitney M. Young Jr. Papers depository, 1973 (Box 79)
    - University of Minnesota Re: Whitney Young, Jr. Papers depository, 1973 (Box 79)
    - Schomburg Center for Research (NY Public Library) Re Young Papers depository, 1973 (Box 79)
- Series IX: Whitney Young, Senior 1976
  - Memorial Reunion, condolence and miscellaneous (Box 79)
  - Mary Elizabeth Lee Thesis re. Whitney Yorung, Sr., April 1983, (2 folders ) (Box 79)
- Series X: Margaret B Young Files
  - Articles by and about Margaret B. Young (Box 80)
  - Awards to MBY (Box 80)
  - Speeches by MBY, 1972 to 1979 (Box 80)
  - Speeches by MBY, 1980 to 1991 (Box 80)
  - Speeches by MBY, KSU Alumni Association Luncheon, 7/13/85 (Box 80)
  - Speeches by MBY (Box 80)
  - Speeches: UNESCO, 1980 to 1991 (Box 81)
  - United Nations International School, (Fund Committee), 1972 (Box 81)
  - United Nations Miscellaneous, 1972 to 1980 (Box 81)
  - United Nations Association of the United States, 1973 to 1980 (Box 81)
  - Trip to Nigeria and Ghana, Schedules and Correspondence, 1974 (Box 81)
  - Dedication of the WMY Jr. Memorial Library (Box 81)
  - Trip to Africa by MBY (Nigeria and Ghana) Newspapers and Clippings, 1974 (Box 81)
  - Report on Trip to Eastern Europe, 1974 (Box 82)
  - U.S. National Commission for UNESCO (Box 82)
  - Two Centuries of Black American ArtRemember the Ladies Exhibit (Box 82)
  - Elected Director of Metropolitan Museum, 9/14/76 (Box 82)
  - Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (Box 82)
  - Bennett College Commencement Sunday, May 8, 1977 (Box 82)
  - Trip to Africa with President Carter, March 1978 (Box 82)
  - Washington and Lee University, March 26, 1979 (Box 82)
  - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts (Box 82)
  - NYS Council on the Arts (Box 82)
  - Virginia Union University Founders' Day Observance, 2/10/78 (Box 82)
- Series XI: Audio and Video Tapes
  - William R. Simms Five cassettes of WMY from: 20 Stuyvesant Oval, New York (Box 83)
    [Former Fund Director for the National Urban League]
  - WMY Fellows, Jan 11/12 1975, (3 cassettes) (Box 83)
  - WMY Fellows, 10/23/74, (3 cassettes) (Box 83)
  - Two copies of same cassette -- Side 1: A National Urban League 1981 Annual Conference "Conference Dinner" -- Side 2: A Guest Speaker, Walter E. Fauntroy, US House of Representatives, Washington DC (Box 83)
  - On fellowships, 1980, (2 cassettes) (Box 83)
  - "The ABC's of Black History", (1 cassette) (Box 83)
  - June 21, 1980, (2 tapes) (Box 83)
    ["both tapes blank"]
  - Whitney Young Commemorative Stamp Ceremony, NY,NY, 1/30/81, (1 cassette) (Box 83)
  - Minutes of Board Meeting, 4/16/82, (1 cassette) (Box 83)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 83)
- Series XII: Printed Materials
  - Annual Reviews of Progress, 1983 to 1987 (Box 84)
  - Annual Reviews of Progress, 1987 to 1989 (Box 85)
  - Columbia University Filmography and Information on Annual Reports, (2 books) (Box 86)
  - After Secession: Jefferson Davis and the Failure of Confederate (Box 87, Folder Escott, Paul D.)
  - Nationalism., Louisiana State University Press, Baton Rouge and London, 1978 (Box 87)
  - Escott, Paul D. Slavery Remembered: A Record of Twentieth Century Slave Narratives., The University of North Carolina Press, Chapel Hill, 1979 (Box 87)
  - Information on annual reports, (1 folder ) (Box 87)
  - Columbia University Filmography (Box 87)
  - Clippings, brochures and periodicals (Box 88)
  - Clippings (Box 89)
  - Brochures and Fellowship Directory (Box 90)
  - Photographs and Artwork, miscellaneous (Box 91)
- Series XIII: Oversized Materials
  - 14 plaques and memorabilia (Box 94-97)
  - Sneakers and hard hat (Box 98)
  - To MBY signed by President Jimmy Carter, (1 Scrolled certificate ) (Box 14/05/02)
  - (11 Record Albums) (Box 14/05/02)
  - Young, Margaret, (2 Scrapbooks ) (Box 14/05/02)
  - (3 Photographs) (Box 14/05/02)
  - (2 Calendars) (Box 14/05/02)
  - (4 Posters) (Box 14/05/02)